<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Poole</title>
 <link href="http://getpoole.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://getpoole.com/"/>
 <updated>2015-01-23T15:37:43-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://getpoole.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Mark Otto</name>
   <email>markdotto@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>The Dj Industry Part 2</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com//2015/01/10/the-dj-industry-part-ii/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2015/01/10/the-dj-industry-part-ii</id>
   <content type="html">

&lt;time class=&#39;entry-date&#39; datetime=&#39;2015-01-10T16:07:06-05:00&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;date&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;date-month&#39;&gt;Jan&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#39;date-day&#39;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;date-suffix&#39;&gt;th&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#39;date-year&#39;&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#39;time&#39;&gt;4:07 pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;
        
      &lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/header&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;So last night (a Friday) I did a little more field research, which ended in me partying in the basement of Bowery Electric.  Summary below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beauty Bar (dive on 14th st between 2nd and 3rd ave)
I roll in around 8:30 and talk to the older woman DJing (from 7-11pm). She says she used to spin every week there and now is only asked to spin once per month on the happy hour shift. She says for the 4 hours she works, she makes about $75- but it&amp;rsquo;s not about the money, she does it becaue she loves it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bar 13 (sports bar on 9th and 2nd ave)
This bar is always filled with the &amp;lsquo;I just turned 21 crowd&amp;rsquo;. Cheap drinks and beer pong.  The DJ booth is this awful box at the end of the bar - you can barely see the guy. It&amp;rsquo;s unlikely people know that there is a DJ. In fact, even though I&amp;rsquo;d been there a number of times, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure they ever hired one. I go up to talk to the DJ, his name&amp;rsquo;s Anthony, and he says that he&amp;rsquo;s making less than $200 for over &lt;em&gt;6 hours&lt;/em&gt; of DJing. I ask him how he got hired and he says he knows the guy responsible for hiring the DJs beause they went to college together and that he&amp;rsquo;s actually a tech recruiter by day (interesting). The DJ says the whole business is quite &amp;ldquo;incestuous.&amp;rdquo; You hire who you know. That&amp;rsquo;s nothing new to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solas(9th st between 2nd and 3rd ave)
I sit at the bar and asked the manager about how he hires DJs. He got super cagey once I got to question 3. Anyway the DJ that spins there regularly is apparantly exclusively responsible for hiring any other DJs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whisky Town (~4th and 2nd ave)
The place is empty when I walk in around 10pm. I talk to one of the bartenders for a while- he&amp;rsquo;s very nice. He tells me that one managers hires the DJs for all 4 of the bars, which are under the same management. There are the same people each Thurs, Fri and Sat that regularly spin. He says that if I were to get a job, they&amp;rsquo;d require me to play &amp;ldquo;top-40 generic kind of music just so I know that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;d be getting into.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Von Keller AKA Von (Bowery and Bleaker)
The place is very crowded and people are having a good time. I had a friend who used to DJ here every Wednesday. He played mostly hip hop. I go up to the DJ and ask him how how much he charges?  He takes a beat and before he can answer, I say &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rsquo;d charge more for a private event then something like this&amp;rdquo; he nods n agreement. He said he&amp;rsquo;d charge anywhere from $500-1000 for a private party and hands me his card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bowery Electric (2nd and Bowery)
I was here most of the night and had a generally good time. What I noticed was people were dancing and having a lot of fun. The DJ played mostly top-40, some older songs, some new pop songs that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with but the groups of 22 year olds were singing along to like they were on stage Just because someone plays the crowd-pleasers doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I&amp;rsquo;m not going to enjoy it or that the DJ isn&amp;rsquo;t good. But there are very obvious changes to how a DJ plays a progression of music that regardless of the song selection, distinguish a shitty DJ. And it baffles and hurts when someone in a position as a DJ at a crowded popular bar can&amp;rsquo;t do that bear minimum. For example, the DJ regularly was playing almost the ENTIRE song. Like, it&amp;rsquo;s fine that you played Katy Perry -Last Friday Night- I genuinely like that song but when you&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to &lt;em&gt;the third verse &lt;/em&gt; Seriously, the third verse, you&amp;rsquo;ve done something wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then on the same token, it didn&amp;rsquo;t really matter. People, for the most part, were having a blast. I had a good time dancing and singing along to few of the songs, whereas others made me want to go up there and smash her laptop. They made me genuinely angry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think they crowd was as discerning as me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean in terms of DeeJBase?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 2 types of people in this industry:
1. Those who care about a crowded room where people are drinking and having fun. These people include, pretty much any bar manager, pretty much any DJ, and most consumers of DJ music and nightlife - people like you and me. This is what matters most in a general sense. This is why people at stay out and drink and make the business possible.&lt;br&gt;
2. Then there are people who care not only about having a good time, about drinking and dancing, but about the art of DJing - that appreciate a DJ that doesn&amp;rsquo;t just play &amp;ldquo;crowd pleasers.&amp;rdquo; And even if they stick with top-40 that they play that music in a way that make sense, that they transition seamlessly, that they don&amp;rsquo;t keep them same on for more than 2 minutes, that keeps us interested beyond the cheap shots.  Those people who care- who value &lt;em&gt;the art&lt;/em&gt;, those are the people that I want to bring together - that need a voice. And those people include a subset of bar managers like those at Folly, VIP Room, and Madame X. A subset of nightlife consumers, like myself. And many, not all, but many DJs. Many DJs who have no gigs - who would also work for peanuts and deserve that rush that comes with seeing an elated crowd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s what DeeJBase is for. It&amp;rsquo;s for talented DJs, the people who hire them, and the people who love them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;footer&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;
      
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My Pride And Joy</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com//2015/01/10/my-pride-and-joy/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2015/01/10/my-pride-and-joy</id>
   <content type="html">

&lt;time class=&#39;entry-date&#39; datetime=&#39;2015-01-09T09:35:14-05:00&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;date&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;date-month&#39;&gt;Jan&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#39;date-day&#39;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;date-suffix&#39;&gt;th&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#39;date-year&#39;&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#39;time&#39;&gt;9:35 am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;
        
      &lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/header&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can safely say that &lt;a href= &quot;http://www.deejbase.com&quot;&gt;DeeJBase.com&lt;/a&gt;, my baby, has grown up to be an awesome website. Here are some of my technical milestones over the past month. I have built:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A database with about 250 real NYC DJs with photos and demos from soundcloud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A log-in system allowing human DJ&amp;rsquo;s to claim and control their profiles through in invitation emailing system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;As of yesterday, I was able to use Facebook Graph to cross reference the majority of DJ&amp;rsquo;s in my database with their facbook pages and pull in their number of likes and well as some other info.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A way of filtering through each DJ&amp;rsquo;s tracks&amp;#8217; taglists and finding genres to associate with each DJ based on key words in the tag lists of their tracks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A cool design with a search feature and the ability to filter DJ&amp;rsquo;s by genre and soundcloud followers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A like button connected to my Deejbase facebook page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of the site so far. And honestly it&amp;rsquo;s been a pleasure - to have a vision and at first, have no idea how you are going to get from point a to point b and then building a scaffold, pouring over API documentation, figuring out algorithms on the back end to parse data. Automating something using code that would take a human countless tedious hours to do manually. Then when you feel like getting artsy, making some design changes on the front-end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full-stack web developement is amazing. I. love. it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now I need to get real and put on my business, lean-startup hat. As of two days ago, I had talked to a bunch of other (succesfull and unsuccesful) entrepreneurs for advice but hadn&amp;rsquo;t really interfaced with many potential target customers (venues and event-planners hiring DJs). So that&amp;rsquo;s what I started doing yesterday. I&amp;rsquo;m going to write a separate post about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Predictive Algorithms</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com//2015/01/05/predictive-algorithms/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2015/01/05/predictive-algorithms</id>
   <content type="html">

&lt;time class=&#39;entry-date&#39; datetime=&#39;2015-01-05T10:37:03-05:00&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;date&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;date-month&#39;&gt;Jan&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#39;date-day&#39;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;date-suffix&#39;&gt;th&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#39;date-year&#39;&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#39;time&#39;&gt;10:37 am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;
        
      &lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, you&amp;rsquo;ve got a data set, you say? Some points And you&amp;rsquo;re not sure what do with them. Maybe you have a set of x and y coordinates?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, I had a set of coordinates, each representing the number of an DJs followers on SoundCloud. I had another set of coordinates that represented an DJ&amp;rsquo;s cost per night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to be able to use this data set to be able to predict given an artist&amp;rsquo;s Soundcloud followers count, how much they might cost! So which set is the x and which is the y? And how do I go about this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great Rubyist once said, now we&amp;rsquo;re in math world, so let&amp;rsquo;s go to the Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found these two sites, which combined helped me make my algorithm pretty easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data we have is x and the data we are predicting would be y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this website all you do is plug in your x, y coordinates and it creates for lines of best fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.had2know.com/academics/regression-calculator-statistics-best-fit.html&quot;&gt;http://www.had2know.com/academics/regression-calculator-statistics-best-fit.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;line-numbers&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#39;&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;4 Regression Equations
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;X independent, Y dependent
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;Linear: Y = AX + B:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;Y = 0.2243X + 258.589
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;correlation = 0.9954
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;Exponential: Y = C(D^X):
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;Y = 349.6169(1.0001^X)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;correlation = 0.8647
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;Power: Y = E(X^F):
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;Y = 31.8027(X^0.4464)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;correlation = 0.8692
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;Logarithmic: Y = G + H(Ln(X)):
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;Y = -3363.0363 + 713.5463Ln(X)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;correlation = 0.7238
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then you can use this site to graph them - which isn&amp;rsquo;t technically necessary but it helped me see which type of line seemed to make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mathsisfun.com/data/grapher-equation.html&quot;&gt;http://www.mathsisfun.com/data/grapher-equation.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty neat and helped me discover the following method aka my predictive algorithm. (sdcl_followers is an attribute of a Dj.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;line-numbers&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#39;ruby&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Dj&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;ActiveRecord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Base&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;rate_get&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;29&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3447&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sdcl_followers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;4635&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That all said, this algorithm is pretty shit. It turns out soundcloud followers isn&amp;rsquo;t the greatest determiner of cost/night. I&amp;rsquo;ll need to take some other factors into account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this is helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Entrepreneur Dot New</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com//2014/12/15/entrepreneur-dot-new/"/>
   <updated>2014-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2014/12/15/entrepreneur-dot-new</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an entrepreneur. I don&amp;rsquo;t yet have a successful business. But I am building one. Using Lean Startup methodology a la Eric Reise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly what the end product I build will be or look like, just that there is a problem in the NYC DJ Market, an information gap so to speak. And it needs to be closed. There are far too many talented DJs and far too many places hiring shitty acts. There are far too many middle men where there needn&amp;rsquo;t be. Not enough data on how good a DJ is, how much they should be hired for, and where to find them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to build a product that solves this market inefficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built a preliminary product, or MVP (minimum viable product). It&amp;rsquo;s the skeleton of a hiring network. There&amp;rsquo;s just no data in it (making it useless). The next step, therefore, is getting a ton of data on NYC DJs to present to NYC venues (my customer) to use as a hiring tool (think Elance for DJs). I figure once venues are using the product, then it won&amp;rsquo;t be hard to convince aspiring DJs to sign up on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past few weeks, I was trying to figure out how to get this data as quickly as possible, so that I can  quickly measure how the customer responds to the product and revamp the product based on that new knowledge (Eric Reise&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;build, measure, learn&amp;rsquo; feedback loop). Today, I poured over Spotify and Soundcloud API docs and what I learned was promising. I may be able to get most of the data I need pretty easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for part II of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Entrepreneurship is a special kind of insanity&amp;rdquo; -me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 1/9/15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized I never followed up on this post. Shortly after I wrote part I, I was able to get around 250 djs in my database from SoundCloud&amp;rsquo;s api!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How? Out of 8000 possible users I could have added, I filtered for ones that indicated they were in NY, included contact info in their bios and had a paid plan- this was my best way of distinguishing between regular users - aka non-DJs - and DJs. This way of filtering ended up working fairly well, although I had to do some manual filtering out of agencys and non-music related entities that also have accounts on SoundCloud (e.g. New York Magazine, Def Records). I also have a Tracks table and have taken about 5 demos for each DJ using their SoundCloud IDs. I was pretty psyched when that all worked out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Infinite Loop Dreams</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com//2014/10/02/infinite-loop-dreams/"/>
   <updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/2014/10/02/infinite-loop-dreams</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;time class=&#39;entry-date&#39; datetime=&#39;2014-10-07T07:48:57-04:00&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;date&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;date-month&#39;&gt;Oct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#39;date-day&#39;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;date-suffix&#39;&gt;th&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#39;date-year&#39;&gt;2014&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#39;time&#39;&gt;7:48 am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;
        
      &lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/header&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How do I get out&amp;hellip;how do I get out? If I don&amp;rsquo;t exit this loop, I won&amp;rsquo;t get up in time for school. What code do I need!?!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;line-numbers&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#39;ruby&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#nonsense code&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Sarah&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;really&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;crazy&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keep&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sleeping&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;crazy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I wake up in a panic, but also happy I&amp;rsquo;m out of that damn inifinite loop trying to sabotage my life. 12:13am. I&amp;rsquo;ve been asleep for an hour and a half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I go back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides leading to a questioning of my sanity, this dream made me ponder why exactly infinite loops exist in Ruby and other coding languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would such a thoughtful, powerful thing allow you to do something which could break it? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Ruby be able to do an unoticeably fast scan of your code before it interprets each line to check for an inifinite loop and let you know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not suggesting that it should. I&amp;rsquo;m just trying to wrap my head around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give me a second while I google this&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok. I&amp;rsquo;m back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparantly, Alan Turing thought of this problem before the advent of modern computers&amp;hellip;in 1936!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem of determining whether a loop is infinite or not is called &amp;ldquo;The halting problem&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that an algorithm to solve this problem cannot exist. &amp;ldquo;One approach to the problem might be to run the program for some number of steps and check if it halts. But if the program does not halt, it is unknown whether the program will eventually halt or run forever.&amp;rdquo;- wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically the computer can never know whether at some point the loop will end or not. Maybe if it keeps going, in 3 years the loop will end. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t know that for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although still, you&amp;rsquo;d think there are certain circumstances where we could know for sure that the loop is inifinite and tell the computer to recognize those instances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;line-numbers&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#39;ruby&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;sarah&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;looping forever&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;looping&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;forever&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;looping&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;forever&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;looping&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;forever&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Wow, don&amp;rsquo;t want to do that again. This must have run 1000 times in irb in the time that it took me to hit control+c and abort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given a loop like the one above, can&amp;rsquo;t we tell Ruby to flag it in some way? I assume there is a way to do that. I assume it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be extremely difficult to do. But there would probably be consequences. By doing that, we&amp;rsquo;d be setting limits on ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe there are things we do want to run forever until we define some other code to stop it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The halting problem is a symbol of the power we have over our computers. If we want the computer to repeat something a bizzillion times till we tell it to stop, we can. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any friends that I can say the same for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, in Ruby, this is not a problem I find myself having very often anway. We can iterate using the .each and .times methods, which can allow us to circumvent &amp;ldquo;while&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;line-numbers&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#39;line-number&#39;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&#39;code&#39;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#39;ruby&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;263&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;crzyyyyyyy&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;times&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;264&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;take it easy, bra&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;265&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;?&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;take&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;easy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bra&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;take&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;easy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bra&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;take&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;easy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bra&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;take&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;easy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bra&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;take&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;easy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bra&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;take&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;easy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bra&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;take&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;easy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bra&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;take&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;easy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bra&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;take&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;easy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bra&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;take&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;easy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bra&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;line&#39;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;footer&gt;
      
  

&lt;span class=&quot;byline author vcard&quot;&gt;Posted by &lt;span class=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;Sarah Stroh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

      

  
  &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/share&quot; class=&quot;twitter-share-button&quot; data-url=&quot;http://strohy1210.github.io/blog/2014/10/07/infinite-loop/&quot; data-via=&quot;&quot; data-counturl=&quot;http://strohy1210.github.io/blog/2014/10/07/infinite-loop/&quot; &gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
  
 
&lt;/footer&gt;

  &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;
    (function(){
      var twitterWidgets = document.createElement(&#39;script&#39;);
      twitterWidgets.type = &#39;text/javascript&#39;;
      twitterWidgets.async = true;
      twitterWidgets.src = &#39;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#39;;
      document.getElementsByTagName(&#39;head&#39;)[0].appendChild(twitterWidgets);
    })();
  &lt;/script&gt;





&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
